A Way of Life
Quadrophenia is a drama, music film directed by Franc Roddam.
Based on the 1973 rock opera album of the same name by The
Who, this is the story of 60s teenager Jimmy.
At work he slaves in a dead-end job.
While after, he shops for tailored suits and rides his
scooter as part of the London Mod scene.
James Michael 'Jimmy' Cooper, played by Phil Daniels.
Steph, played by Leslie Ash.
Chalky, played by Phil Davis.
Dave, played by Mark Wingett.
Ace Face, played by Sting.
Kevin, played by Ray Winstone.
Quadrophenia is a 1979 British drama film, based on the
Who's 1973 rock opera of the same name.
It was directed by Franc Roddam in his feature directing debut.
Unlike the adaptation of Tommy, Quadrophenia is not a musical
film, and the band does not appear live in the film.
The film, set in London in 1964, depicts a period of emotional turmoil in the life of Jimmy Cooper (Phil Daniels), a young mod who escapes
from his dead-end job as a postroom boy by dancing, partying, abusing Dexamyl, riding scooters and brawling with rockers.
The film explores themes of london, england, england,
woodstock, new york, music festival, mods.
The tone is emotional.